In this clip, all we're doing is simply putting the kite away.
We just went out on the water, had a sick session, great day.
But, basically, we want to make sure that we are going to put this kite away in a fashion that's going to promote us going out and doing that again real nice and easy next time.
So, just to keep good bridle maintenance here and make sure nothing's getting too twisted, I'm going to detach these lines and I'm going to reattach the bridles to each other.
That way, one bridle can't get intertwined within itself and I know everything is just going to be exactly the way I left it next time I pull this kite out.
So, I go ahead, I detach those lines and just attach these two bridles just to each other like that.
Go over here to this other one, do the same thing.
And, if you look at the kite, you can see that this kite has a good amount of sand on it.
I use my kite everyday it's windy and I need to make sure that these kites are always in proper working order.
So, in order to, you know, really assure that and make sure, you know, that it's absolutely up to par every time I need it to be, I keep absolutely perfect care of my kites.
I will never put them away if they are sandy.
And, if they are wet when I get home, I make sure I let them out to dry.
Really important is, if your kite is wet with salt water, it's not necessarily the worst thing in the world, these kites are made to be wet, obviously, you use them in the water all the time, but salt water actually doesn't mould.
That's the big thing about it.
So, if it's wet with salt water, you can put it away and that's alright.
But if it rains on it or you're kiting somewhere in the Great Lakes or somewhere where it's just fresh water, make sure when you put the kite away, you're putting away a dry kite.
Because the next time you open your bag and pull out your kite, all of a sudden, you're going to find all this nasty mould wrapped around the entire thing.
I reach forward, grab my bar and I'm going to sort of reel up this last little bit of excess line and then just, you know, anyway I can, just kind of hitch it off, tuck it through, and make sure this excess sort of little ends right here.